<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Large Evolving Networks</title>
      <link>/project/network-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/network-clustering/</guid>
      <description>One of the most significant problems in network sciences is clustering or community detection. It is a principle tool for exploratory data analysis and is also crucial for applications such as image processing, server load balancing, and several other areas. Theoretical guarantees on network clustering show that many popular methods are statistically accurate for very large networks. However, one often overlooks the fact that such methods are quite inefficient for large scale applications, and hence, practically efficient clustering algorithms deviate significantly from the theoretically studied methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Testing for Networks</title>
      <link>/project/network-twosampletesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/network-twosampletesting/</guid>
      <description>We study the problem of testing whether two large graphs are generated from the same model. This problem lies behind the question of whether brain network of Alzheimer patients differ from those of healthy individuals. On the applied end, we proposed new two-sample tests to compare graphs / graph populations. Our theory resolved a fundamental question – when can we test large networks without access to multiple independent samples? We used statistical minimax theory to show that solvability of a testing problem with limited data depends crucially on the hypotheses under consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering: From Subspaces to Hypergraphs</title>
      <link>/project/hypergraph-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hypergraph-clustering/</guid>
      <description>The project focussed on the problem of clustering complex networks that can be modelled as hypergraphs. Clustering hypergraphs has a long history, and a wide range of applications including motion segmentation, categorical data clustering and VLSI circuit partitioning. However, the theory of this problem was not well studied. My works are among the first studies on consistency of practical hypergraph clustering algorithms under a random planted community model. Along with proving theoretical guarantees, we also proposed efficient algorithms that achieve states-of-the-art results in motion segmentation and subspace clusterin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic optimization with smoothing</title>
      <link>/project/optimization-qgaussian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/optimization-qgaussian/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic optimization is the mathematical tool for solving reinforcement learning problems, where the goal is to optimize the long-run performance of a dynamical system. We proposed new methods for stochastic optimization that estimate the gradient and Hessian of the cost function through a smoothing based on some generalised Gaussian distributions. The works provide convergence analysis and numerical performance of our algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>