<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Group on Debarghya Ghoshdastidar</title>
    <link>/group/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Group on Debarghya Ghoshdastidar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Foundations of AI</title>
      <link>/group/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/hero/</guid>
      <description>TUM Department of Informatics Technical University of Munich</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>/group/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/focus/</guid>
      <description>The research group works on the statistical theory of machine learning and artificial intelligence, We provide mathematical understanding of learning algorithms, thereby establishing black-box AI tools as formal statistical principles. Our research focuses on three aspects of data science in the present era of big data analysis.
 Data complexity: Many applications involve complex data, such as relational information, texts etc., that often lack natural Euclidean structure. Hence, learning from such data require non-parametric approaches or representation learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>/group/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/members/</guid>
      <description> Debarghya Ghoshdastidar (Professor) Claudia Link (Administration) Leena Vankadara (PhD student, jointly with Ulrike von Luxburg)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/group/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research opportunities</title>
      <link>/group/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/jobs/</guid>
      <description>Open positions Internship We have an open 3 month internship in our group. The project is about similarity measures between graphs. The funding only covers the internship, and hence, it is suitable for students in Munich or T&amp;uuml;bingen.
Other funding opportunities We are always looking for people interested in working on machine learning and its theory. If there are no advertised openings, you may still join our group with others scholarships.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>